ANEELA OAD

SALESFORCE & WEB DEVELOPER

PROFILE

A qualified and professional web & Salesforce developer with 2 years' experience in administration and development, specialized in developing custom applications for the web and Salesforce. My life revolves around programming, coding, and designing. A detail-oriented team player

M @aneelaoad

✓ aneelaoadd@gmail.com

03153270252

Xarachi, Pakistan

aneela-codes

in aneela-oad

EXPERIENCE

SALESFORCE DEVELOPER | DevCreatives++, Karachi 2021 - 2022

- Developing customized solutions within the Salesforce platform
- Designing, coding, and implementing Salesforce applications
- · Creating timelines and development goals
- · Troubleshooting and fixing bugs

LEVEL ONE SELLER | Fiverr

2021 - Present

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SYSTEMS

Mehran University of Engineering & Technology, Jamshoro

2018 - 2022

PRE-ENGINEERING

osar Foundation School

2016 - 2018

TECHNOLOGIES

Style Frameworks: SASS, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, Lightning Design System (LDS)

JS Frameworks/Libraries: JQuery, ReactJS, Lightning Web Components (LWC)

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Apex, Python, Java

Databases: SOQL, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools: Git, Postman, VS Code

Dashboards: Einstein Analytics, Tableau Analytics

PROJECTS

PROJECT 1: IOT BASED GARBAGE COLLECTOR AND DISPOSAL BOT

Final Year Project **Duration:** 1 year

Technologies Used: Python, MG995 servo motor, Arduino Mega, Blue-tooth module, ESP32 Cam, XL4015 power module, a88 metal module, MIT inventor

Description: This project was built to provide a cost-effective autonomous garbage collecting bot, which can easily identify obstacles and differentiate between garbage and no garbage objects and dispose them in the nearest bin. It has two modes, autonomous and manual. When garbage crosses limit, a warning is sent. Ultrasonic sensors detect obstacles and DC motors move the bot according to the desired movement. s. Arduino Mega board is used for the processing and controlling and it commands the driver IC to activate the motor. Camera and OpenCV are used for detection of hands.

PROJECT 2: WHATSAPP INTEGRATION WITH LIGHTNING WEB COMPONENTS (LWC)

Client's Project

Duration: 1 month

Technologies Used: JavaScript, Apex, Lightning Web Components, Glitch Server, WhatsApp Business API

Description: The app is build using Lightning web components and WhatsApp Messenger is integrated using the WhatsApp Business Api. Meta developer account is used to generate the access token and test phone number with message template. The LWC is created named WhatsApp Integration to create the basic UI of sending message. Then the apex class is created for API callouts

PROJECT 3: POKEMON TRACKER APP

Client's Project **Duration:** 1 month

Technologies Used: JavaScript, Apex, Lightning Web Components, SLD, CSS

Description: The objective of the app is to track down the pokemons by using their trainers' details. Thus two objects are used: Contact as Pokemon Trainer and Pokemon_c (Standard & Custom). Three components: PokemonLocation, PokemonCards and TrainerDetailsRecordForm and one apex class: PokemonDetailsClass are built to make this functional app.

PORTFOLIO

Visit the portfolio for more projects
https://aneela-oad.github.io/personal-web/